[Music]
you're watching notepad and I'm your
host Ibrahim sunny today we will have a
chat with many life asset management
Jason Chong is joining us to discuss not
just about their firm but also to have a
look at the industry as well
decent thanks very much for taking the
time to speak with us the interesting
developments over the year in Malaysia
has indeed been remarkable we've seen
stronger than normal growth figures
we've seen the government introducing
very very lofty ideals and ideas through
the shared prosperity programme we've
also seen the Finance Minister
presenting an interesting budget you
know one or two weeks ago how do you
encapsulate this leading towards the end
of the year how do you you know
summarize this into how you want to
manage 2020 moving forward I think then
the new government took over last year
they put back a lot of the government
projects and that cost the economy
disorder but over the course of the last
18 months or so I think they revived
some of this mega projects and on the
back of that we think that the growth
next year would be better right of
course the big caveat is on exports and
with the global economy slowing down
exports will be affected and hence you
know we need more domestic factors to
keep the economy but as we see over the
past few months and asteroids in the
budget the government is increasingly
off the appetite to get Malaysian
exporters out there market we've seen
statements coming across from various
players saying that because of trade war
between the US and China a lot of these
two nations are not talking to other
countries to get more goods and services
are off how do we read the uncertainty
coming up from the trade war and the
posturing of the government trying to
make Malaysians to export their stuff
more to China or
where else I think it's we are I mean I
just I was in denying this a couple of
weeks ago hmm and I was talking to this
person that works there and he was
saying and in the electronic sector so
he was saying that a lot of the Western
semiconductor companies are actually
expanding their capacity so I mean we
talked about you know a Malaysia being a
beneficiary of the trade war and I think
that's a very good example you know some
of the electronic companies there are
also doing very well and again it's on
the back of you know what's happening
with the trade war as well
so we have seen pockets of potential
growth areas I just want to highlight
again the statistics interesting E&E
still remains to be our biggest export
out despite the fact that you know we
keep on talking about palm oil and their
hairs and everything else and he's
critical to this but the perennial
argument is industries like the yen e
we're still down there in the value
chain we're not really up there in terms
of building a I'd ships and many others
I mean Honda hi Foxconn whatever while
we wants to use these kind of chips
we're not developing that do you think
that now is the time because of the I
guess quarrel between US and China
perhaps it's time for any players
particularly Melissa to just boost their
capacity and not just be on the lower
end of the value chain move up yeah I
think you're right I think that's
generally the direction that the Gama
wants to take in terms of you know for
Malaysian manufacturers to climb the
value-add curve right I think generally
if you look at Malaysian entrepreneurs
they've been a bit more cautious in
their approach you know so I think they
need to take a bit more risk and and
grow more rapidly especially now there's
the disability with the trig whoa yes I
I do agree with you that Malaysia needs
to step up especially on the electronic
side where we do have some advantage and
we already in that industry and based on
the observation as we mentioned in
eliminating there are some opportunities
that can be as a team because the
numbers are there anyway the demand
let's talk a little bit about many like
this yeah how have
sorted out your portfolio equity versus
fixed income are you okay
about the whole situation Malaysian
equity as you know somebody joked right
the most vibrant academic in the world
but yeah if you look at Malaysia as a
whole set to say our Malaysian market
has not done very well for us as an
investment house and being part of a
global asset management company the
advice to our customers that one needs
to diversify the local having both a
local and foreign investments also
having both equity and fixed income
because in this day and age you know
every day you wake up you know you don't
know what some people were tweet and
that causes markets to be very volatile
so you need that diversification to
weather the ups and downs so I was when
I just looked at our performance if you
look at our fixed income funds
year-to-date is up 7% I know this is
even higher than some of our equity
funds of course and and with interest
rates being cut and there's one more
expected rate cut towards the end of the
year it's just gonna boost further at
your 7% so what does that mean that
means that you know investors have to
take a cautious approach moving forward
they can't they can't go a little bit
more aggressive I think at this at this
point in time we would advocate what you
call a barbell structure so on one side
we would want to go for your income bias
products why because you want STD
evidence mmm on the other hand you also
want growth so you look for growth
opportunities I see maybe some
semiconductor is a place to be for
import substitution or what's happening
with a trade war hmm you know but so you
want a balance of both type of
strategies in this kind of market we'll
take a short break when we come back
we'll discuss more on REITs and which
isn't wrong of many life
[Music]
thanks for staying on with us you're
watching note pattern today I'm with
Jason Chong we see you off many life
asset management Jason just not you
touched a little bit about
diversification of investment and you're
talking about
REITs being interesting for you and of
course let me tell you might start about
my you know my experience on breeds and
I have a few investments in my portfolio
and I tried a few years ago just ripe
one year one dream and it gave me a
positive return not to say that it was
like anything but I figured it's okay I
don't understand and quite understand
how this can be beneficial for me in the
long run so I pulled it out invested in
something else
was that a good strategy no I think if
you hang on to if you hang on to that
investments in which you would have done
very well you know why because if you
look at the returns on Ritz in general
they've been using us anywhere from four
to six percent depending on which
particular Ritenour that you're
investing in but if you take our Asia
Pacific rib for example rich fund that
we have over the last 10 years that fund
has generated a fifteen percent per
annum return that's crazy on average and
this is not like when you're up another
year down yeah it's been pretty
consistent it's not like forty percent
and then our what two percent now so
we're looking at very balanced curve
correct and the reason for that is that
you know RIT is what you are doing is
that you are investing in yielding
properties you know bit office buildings
shopping complexes and and so forth so
all these assets give you regular income
and the beauty about this assets is that
you also get to enjoy capital gains in
the medium to long term because Papa T
values go up and the other Vantage of
risk as opposed to investing in
properties yourself is that with Ritz
you get the you don't have to have a lot
of money to have a diversified portfolio
of different types of asset classes in
are you got your
retail your shopping malls your condos
whatever it is but also rich do not pay
corporate tax the rule if or the law is
if you distribute more than 90 percent
of your of your profits its dividend to
to your shareholders you don't pay
corporate tax
yeah so you get higher payout because
they had to declare 90 percent or more
the earnings and it's tax-free you don't
you can get that by investing in
property no sir you know of course you
have to prop against Eric so many of
this yeah precisely so those are the
advantages of Ritz and you know Ritz
have done well not only in Malaysia but
throughout the world mainly because you
know big global interest rates coming
down everyone is looking for for for
safety for stability for returns that
are hopefully better than what you can
get by putting money in the bank
there's many life offer the possibility
of your customers investing in REITs
overseas yes so like right now we have
an asia-pacific rid yeah at the
beginning of this year we launched the
first global Sharia rig in the world
okay right the returns come in here oh
yeah so we launched the fun in March
this year
okay so much to date the fun is up 7% no
yeah
this is asia-pacific oh no this is no
this is a global one all right so we
talked about two things yeah so global
yes and the Egypt and the other
conventional rate is is asia-pac so if
you look at the asia-pac rate here today
okay that's a full year full
year-to-date performance that fund is up
17% on the year-to-date basis 17% yes
that's crazy
I'm sorry this is efficient in running
oh no no this fun has been wrong for ten
years or more
okay yeah this is this is interesting
right so how do you populate that
particular portfolio you eyeball
everything or you go with what the
market says how do you make sure that
you choose the right necessary based
treats
so again is about diversification in
terms of countries because you'd want to
put all your eggs
to one basket yeah and also in different
classes of of ribs or properties to
invest in so right now our our five
managers are overweight or bullish on
the office space in Singapore and
Australia and on the commercial side
right
we prefer necessity malls so neccessity
malls those that okay you know if you're
in Hong Kong or in Singapore you don't
agree on like in Malaysia we can go to
wet market buy our groceries there
everything is it more right so Nessus
demos are those that have your
supermarket chains in it and come with
me whether they come is doing good or
bad you still need to go to the mall and
buy all your necessities so in good
times and bad times right you know that
this this malls will do well again
you're talking about sorry there's a
theme coming in from your speech right
now income generating businesses would
be critical yes
okay is this for instance the Asia
Pacific fund or the Asia Pacific Reed
does it include Japan as well in our
particular fund it does not include
Japan and was because using Japan are
not as attractive as other parts of Asia
so the general yeah the general interest
rates there are a lot more what about
the sharing of fun what's when you say
global is too big for me to grasp what
kind of areas you go to so the biggest
portion is in the States then we have
Europe we've got Europe UK Australia so
it's the major that the major economies
and some portion in Asia as well how
sensitive our investors when it comes to
share compliancy for reads okay so we
are the the share of it is basically
created more for our our Asian or Asian
neighbors Malaysia and Indonesia because
we share the same shara principles okay
but we've been getting interest even
from the middle east on this global
sherry fund that we have okay right but
there's always the
differential in standards or Sharia
understanding or sharing an approval
between Middle Easterners yes correct
so that is the the challenge and making
sure that you know we we comply so we
are not saying that no we are going to
sell it to the me to the Middle East but
you know we are exploring that because
they are requests yeah and also we are
looking into that area as well does this
mean that your Sharia compliance is is
being overlooked by the Sharia Board of
been together as well oh yes so because
our product was meant for the Malaysian
market yeah so it complies customers yes
for retail customers okay so it
definitely complies with our local
Sharia laws okay
yeah that's crazy and how do you expect
this particular market to grow do you
think that you'll grow very bullish Li
or it's just going to be very linear in
terms of growth so the rib market is
actually very interesting especially
view if you talk about if you look at
the global share it yeah so you know if
you look at the new economies today what
are the new economies talk about
internet and e-commerce but little
internet e-commerce but if you take one
step back you know you they talk about
cloud cloud storage but you know that
cloud storage is actually a physical
server simple sounds do mean somewhere
right right so in the u.s. that's one of
the fastest growing areas we had a lot
of warehouses for service right because
you need to store your physical service
you and I mean things like that it's
also growing in Asia suppose ecommerce
as well you need distribution hubs where
you need a big literally a platform for
you to deliver goods and services so the
growth areas is places to store your
servers warehouses to saw your your
goose before you deliver to customers
telecommunication towers Network yeah
right especially five-year round the
corner so this are all apart from your
brick-and-mortar normal malls and
condominiums and hospitals and all that
stuff yeah so when we launched the the
global rid you know it gives us an eye
into
where are the future growth areas for
the rig industry in in Asia yeah so in
the US for example there are specialty
writs that actually it can be a prison
yeah you can never writ write write that
many just a prison so it's something
that when I first heard about it it's
like wow okay you know but it just opens
up your your your your - to what read
opportunities are and there's a lot of
growth potential the one very
interesting interview that I heard very
recently was of Schwartzman the CEO of
Blackrock Blackstone and Blackstone and
you know one of the biggest if not the
biggest investment managers out there
they are the world's biggest warehouse
owners as it blew me away when we talked
about that right and and and you know
one of the explanation that Schwartzman
gave for the CEO of Blackstone gave was
that it's all about the Internet and the
Internet is about warehouses all right
it's just bizarre that you know when you
think about the future or modern way of
doing things it's actually the brick and
mortar that matters the most right so in
very interesting we'll take a short
break when we come back we'll clone
crude our conversation with Jason Chong
of many lines
[Music]
thanks for staying on with us I'm Jason
Chung of many life let's talk about 2024
the retail investor when you know when
they want to measure or take stock into
the kind of macro economic tivities as
well as micro stuff that's happening
right now how do they navigate 2020
early on because I guess you know
towards the end of the year a lot of
people have wrapped up the kind of
investment ideas moving forward for next
year how do you think they should
navigate I think that's a very
challenging question because of all the
uncertainties I mean a lot depends on
the trade war how they evolves so as I
mentioned earlier you know because
there's so much uncertainty this is very
it's very hard to say that we have one
strategy and we're going to know and we
make that decision now we have to be a
bit more versatile and agile in the way
of thinking here yeah and the idea is to
basically be defensive look for
companies with a weekly cash flow you
know that can that can they can survive
the ups and downs yeah you know income
yielding assets like risks that we just
talked about and you know for for
additional alpha we look for specific
opportunities so I won't think it's I I
don't think that it's more of a top-down
driven thing it's more of a bottom-up
and where you can find deadly I just
want to pick your brain so what do you
think about Robo advisors at this point
I'm ok this is a very interesting topic
so I'm of the view that investment
products are sold and not bought what
that means okay is that you know
investment products are complicated and
you mean able to do your research but
there will still be questions especially
if you're not from the investment
industry what all the technical jargon
is so in my view you still need someone
there to explain to you what the
investment is all about like what we
just talked about so I feel that Robo
advisor E or FinTech would be more of a
tool to assist investment professionals
to to be city educate customers but
replace them the way it's marketed is
that you cut the middleman you cut the
investment manager out and the customers
can just jump in on the bandwagon invest
straight up and Robo advisors you don't
have to know anything Blanc the money
there everything is gonna be figured out
for you so that's very interesting so if
you look at the thin tax or the Robo
advisors do you know that a lot them
have had to close down or they've been
already being bought up by traditional
money managers yeah hence the question I
ask you because I can't make sense of
this yeah I mean they are regulated by
whatever market they operate in Malaysia
we have one or two Robo advisors
well-regulated by Scottish Commission
all right but what do you think about
them do you think that you know maybe we
need we still need human beings to talk
us through things I think so but maybe
I'm biased become an asset management
company no it's fine you just want to
know more right yeah the key selling
point here is the fees that people need
to pay you know when we talk about asset
managers okay fine gotta pay asset
managers out there but if the returns
are like double digits I guess I can
live with to 3% 5% whatever right then
the net would be 70% whatever but Robo
advisors cut that I'm still gonna you
know get some percents that's the idea
where we look at you know how do we sort
out these kind of investment strategies
a lot of people my parents included they
don't want to go in through a web
browser it's not because the these don't
trust the whole system you can trust it
wouldn't but at some point we got to
talk more about this right yeah I think
to be fair okay I have not know what to
put you in the position yeah so I mean
to be fair I've not done my my research
in a sense of what kind of returns have
robot advices January
vs active fund manager yeah so I I will
reserve my comment on that whether they
are January across definitely the fees
are lower yeah yeah but are they
generally generating the returns another
investors are looking for and of course
the final question they don't ask you
for this interview it's been interesting
composition actually is on investing
overseas
yes we've touched a little bit about
reeds and many others
but we've seen the posturing from PNB
khazana as well as CPF that they want to
diversify the portfolio even further
because of instructions from previous
administration they have to invest more
locally now the seems like they have a
little bit more mandate to invest
overseas but that's an institutional
investors but people watching this
interview do you think that it's about
time for us to start looking
aggressively if not read something else
but aggressively towards investing
overseas definitely I think you need to
diversify I mean that's the message that
I'm sending up to all my friends why
because you know things are so volatile
you can't put all your eggs in one
basket you know in that way that is
Malaysia or Singapore you you need that
diversification in terms of asset
classes and geographical reach at least
you get a more balanced income is that
anytime we go outside we're discounted
for point two times so you know I want
to buy a thousand dollars of something
as 4020 for me bring it correct but is
this a hurdle that we have to push to no
matter what
yes you have to so again the
pacification not only means asset
classes but also currency so you're
right so if you wonder hate against the
ringgit invest offshore yeah right then
you get that you get that written back
for the times if not more yeah all right
what could be less it's all about
diversification yes okay that was an
interesting conversation I was speaking
with Jason shown the co-main a knife
asset management if you've missed any
part of this activity sit onto a straw
when you're calm for notepad there you
can also watch these kind of interviews
on the astrology app just down look
where wherever you get the application
on your mobile phone thanks very much
for watching until next time
[Music]